Vajiha Hameed **Data Analyst**

Inquisitive data analyst with 7 years experience in the third sector, interpreting data to solve business problems through insights. My love of data lead me to take time away from my last role, to refocus on mastering my data science skills.

vajihahameed@gmail.com | © 07917842480 |



vajihahameed.github.io



Skills

Python, SQL, HTML Languages:

NumPy, Pandas, MatPlotLib, Seaborn, Plotly, Scikit-Learn, BeautifulSoup, SciPy, Jupyter, Excel, Salesforce, Tableau Framework:

Data: Data mining, exploration and visualisation, web-scraping, statistical modelling, machine learning

Work Experience

Aug 2019

Data Analyst | Portfolio of projects (vajihahameed.github.io) include:

- Present

• Analysis of Michelin starred restaurants worldwide:

Extensive web-scraping, data cleaning and data analysis of unstructured data to establish patterns and correlation across The Michelin Guide world-wide and The World's 50 Best Restaurants using Plotly, Pandas and BeautifulSoup.

Mental health services access by BME population:

Analysis and statistical testing of significance of the access to mental health services by BME communities in the UK, using Python, MatPlotLib and SciPy.

House prices predictor:

Predicting Iowa house prices using advanced regression techniques in Sci-Kit Learn. Data exploration using Python, Seaborn, NumPy and Pandas.

Community Fundraising Manager | The Brain Tumour Charity 2014-2019

- Spearheaded data and market analysis, identifying key metrics and trends. Proposed and implemented 3 new initiatives into the Community Fundraising strategy, increasing acquisition and retention by 25%.
- Working with structured and unstructured data, analysed The Twilight Walk series, where insights and proposals resulted in a 200% increase in participation the following year.
- Database team lead Data reporting, presenting business proposals to management, creating Excel and Salesforce dashboards, training team members on improving data management.
- Managed a team across half of the UK, responsible for income target of £1.5m across the region.
- Lead on strategy, workflow and implementation of key fundraising campaigns across the UK.
- Built and maintained close relationships with key stakeholders.
- Presenting in front of large and small audiences.
- Emotional support to those affected by a brain tumour.

2012-2014 Charity Validation Executive | Localgiving

- Analysed trends in charitable giving across London boroughs, implementing a business plan to attract more BME donors and subscribers to the platform.
- Data analysis of charity memberships
- Executed and managed validation process ensuring eligibility, HMRC and governance compliance
- Built library of workflows and models to ensure consistent business management
- Line management and Account management of stakeholders and external partners
- Development and delivery of fundraising, social media and marketing training to charity members.

Education

2007-2011 Mathematics BSc (Hons), University of Nottingham

Certifications and Courses

2020 Tableau A-Z, Udemy

2020 Tableau Advanced Training, Udemy

2019 Data Science Track, Codecademy

2018 Data Security Awareness Level 1, NHS Digital

2017 **Diploma in Fundraising**, Institute of Fundraising